<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>Laidout</title>
      <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
      <description>Laidout</description>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <pubDate>15 June 2006</pubDate>                 <!-- time of last publication -->
      <lastBuildDate>15 June 2006</lastBuildDate>    <!-- time of last update      -->
      <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
      <webMaster>tomscoding@gmail.com</webMaster>
      <image>
          <title>Laidout</title>
          <url>http://www.laidout.org/laidout-icon-16x16.png</url>
          <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
          <width>16</width>
          <height>16</height>
          <description>Laidout</description>
      </image>


      <item>
         <title>Spring...</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>

	&lt;br&gt;
	Here&apos;s a short video tour of a freshly debugged clone tiler in Laidout. Unfortunately,
	I am unable to attend the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.libregraphicsmeeting.org&quot;&gt;Libre Graphics Meeting&lt;/a&gt; this year, so instead, in sympathy I&apos;m doing a 
	bit of a debugging sprint. Next on the list is debugging the new text tools, and	implementing proper file exporters for them.&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;280&quot; height=&quot;157&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p7QHnWeN-Ys&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
		 </description>
         <pubDate>15 April 2017</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 15 April 2017</guid>
      </item>



      <item>
         <title>Libre Graphics Meeting Recap</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
This year&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laidout.org&quot;&gt;LGM&lt;/a&gt; in London has come and gone. It&apos;s always
interesting to see what other projects are working on, and get a feel for how things
can interoperate.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Thanks to everyone who came to the Laidout Engraving
workshop! A few glitches, but at least a few people were able to get Laidout running enough to play
around with. It was a lesson to me to not take things for granted, and thoroughly test the stuff
you will present, not just expect things that have worked for years to still be working! 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

I also presented the new text tools I&apos;ve been working on, particularly the brand new text on path tool.
Just in the nick of time, I was able to make variable width stroking adjust text glyph heights. Now I
need to smooth out all the shortcuts I took making the tool, and make it work properly with the
rest of Laidout. Also in the works was color font usage. I didn&apos;t quite get my opentype svg color font
functional before LGM, and I&apos;m still working on it. Special thanks to Hin-Tak Leung, who figured
out what was going wrong with my font (obscure unicode mapping difficulties), and also offered
many pointers on how to make Laidout&apos;s build process a little more streamlined. 
         
		 </description>
         <pubDate>23 May 2015</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 23 May 2015</guid>
      </item>






      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.096 Released! Wa-hoo!</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
The biggest change this time is finally switching to &lt;a href=&quot;http://cairographics.org&quot;&gt;cairo&lt;/a&gt; for rendering,
instead of cobbling together hideous Xlib based methods. 
This opens up a variety of rendering finesse, such as the ability for transparent paths, and perhaps more interestingly, a text tool.
I&apos;m sure there are many cairo rendering related bugs hiding out around the edges of Laidout, so please let me know if and when you find them! 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Text caption tool&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After a mere 10 years of Laidout&apos;s existence, there is now a native text tool! It is a bit of a prototype right now. Expect
major improvements as I learn to navigate the huge mass of issues surrounding encoding, rendering, and
exporting text. Currently, each text object must have the same font, color, and size. Exporting to SVG works best. Export to
PDF and Scribus is mediocre, as those suffer from text sizing issues I haven&apos;t figured out yet.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;More export arrangement options&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now there are options to export only even or odd spread numbers, as well as rotate each 
by 90 degree increments or rotate every other spread by 180 degrees. Also, you can export
in reverse order.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Engraver tool&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This tool has numerous refinements, such as being able to use the different modes on many engraver objects at once.
The group stacking has more control over visibility, and groups can now more easily share style resources, like dash patterns
and tracing. Also new is a kind of random field offset applied to the auto line types like radial, circular, linear, and the
new spiral type. One bad thing about the switch to cairo is that the engraver tool is slightly less responsive. The old fast xlib 
screen render does not translate to a fast cairo render, and I need to totally reprogram the previewer.
 That&apos;ll have to wait for the next release. 
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Spread Editor enhancements&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The spread editor is now a little more flexible with page number markers. You can now easily tag pages with markers of different shapes
and colors for simple visual cues to indicate how done you are as you work on them.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;New file dialog&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The File Dialog has been totally reprogrammed, and hopefully is easier to use now, with clearer access to
recent files and bookmarks, and allowing easy change to the preview window size. 
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
         
		 </description>
         <pubDate>18 December 2015</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 18 December 2015</guid>
      </item>





      <item>
         <title>Proto text tool</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
         I&apos;m taking a break from working on the Engraving tool to finish conversion to rendering with cairo,
which makes possible not only better rendering of paths and meshes, but also a text tool! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SjSixSxBW_g&quot;&gt;Here&apos;s a very
basic text tool experiment&lt;/a&gt;, to get my feet wet with the myriad coding issues involved in text layout and fonts.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SjSixSxBW_g&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.laidout.org/screenshots/images/text-tool-start-0.095.1.png&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;232&quot; height=&quot;130&quot; alt=&quot;Simple text tool video demo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		 </description>
         <pubDate>9 October 2015</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 9 October 2015</guid>
      </item>




      <item>
         <title>Engraver tool development</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
There have been numerous refinements happening in the engraving tool, including being able to apply
line profiles, and a kind of fluid random offset. You can see some of this in action in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H8IHg7opOQ4&quot;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.laidout.org/screenshots/images/eels-s.png&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; alt=&quot;Eels&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.laidout.org/screenshots/images/lineprofiles-0.095.1-s.png&quot; width=&quot;175&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; alt=&quot;Line profiles&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.laidout.org/screenshots/images/wavy-monument-s.png&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; alt=&quot;Wavy lines&quot; /&gt;         
		 </description>
         <pubDate>26 July 2015</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 26 July 2015</guid>
      </item>





      


      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.095a Released!</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
This release I have to call a quasi-&quot;stable&quot; release, not quite tested enough to be called just &quot;stable&quot;, 
because I wanted to have something more current than the last release before this
year&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://libregraphicsmeeting.org/2015/&quot;&gt;Libre Graphics Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, in Toronto, April 29 to May 2.
I will be giving a talk about lines on Friday May 1. So, if you are not too tired from dancing around the maypole,
come on down to the University of Toronto to see this and many other interesting talks about open source graphics!   
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
New this time is many improvements to the engraving tool, a revamped spread editor to allow easy page label
marking, and a brand new Path mechanism, which has path offset, variable width, and angle built in.
		 </description>
         <pubDate>22 April 2015</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 22 April 2015</guid>
      </item>




      
      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.094b bug fix...</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
Just released a kind of bug fix for version 0.094. In this one:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed loading bug for tile files for use in the clone tiler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a spiral tiling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ability to define custom page sizes in the Signature Interface. Just click the
   numbers next to the paper name to set up custom width and height.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a freehand interface to create lines, &quot;stroked&quot; lines, or mesh along lines.
   This is more proof of concept right now, and is only accessible when you run
   &lt;tt&gt;&lt;b&gt;laidout --experimental&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;. Look for better integration of freehand capability in future releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
		 </description>
         <pubDate>14 March 2014</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 14 March 2014</guid>
      </item>





      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.094 released!</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
Laidout Version 0.094 is at last 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laidout.org/#download&quot;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt;, as source or an  
amd64 precompiled deb package, for you to experiment with. As always, Laidout is very much a work in progress.
I finally stopped myself from starting to implement more new tools, in order to squeeze out this release.
Consequently this release is more like a rough draft of many new things. Save often.
I try to fix any bugs people tell me about, so when you find some, please let me know at
&lt;a href=&quot;#contact&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
This release has taken so long on account of a lot of under the hood refactoring, and investigating its potential.
Also there are rough implementations of a variety of new tools.
New in this release:&lt;br/&gt;
mesh based engraver fill, clone tiler, anchor alignment, graphical shell, and more!
		 </description>
         <pubDate>20 February 2014</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 20 February 2014</guid>
      </item>




      <item>
         <title>Development update</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
         My current new goal is to have a new release of Laidout by the end of this month. It is amazing to me how
quickly time appears to be passing. There are a few relatively simple &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laidout.org/roadmap.html&quot;&gt;items to tick off&lt;/a&gt;.
With any luck, I will reach the goal!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the meantime, please enjoy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VN9L8UYZgGA&amp;feature=c4-overview-vl&amp;list=PL22F7148142927C13&quot;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;
of the substantially reworked signature folder, which allows
stacking and inserting signatures with different base page sizes and different folding patterns,
to form a single book. 

		 </description>
         <pubDate>6 December 2013</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 6 December 2013</guid>
      </item>




      <item>
         <title>Fold paper on the web!! Now!!</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
Fold paper for books on the web! I&apos;m pleased to release a port of the signature folder of Laidout 
to Html5 via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.processingjs.org&quot;&gt;Processing.js 1.4.1&lt;/a&gt;. So, any browser on any platform that can run that reasonable well
 should be able to run this! You might have a few quirks on tiny mobile devices, but hey, 
 this is my first html5 port.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laidout.org/folder&quot;&gt;Click here to start!&lt;/a&gt; It may take a second to load, as it&apos;s a little over half a meg.&lt;br /&gt;
         
		 </description>
         <pubDate>14 August 2013</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 14 August 2013</guid>
      </item>




      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.093 released! Yippee!</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
Laidout Version 0.093 is at last 
available, as source or an  
amd64 precompiled deb package, for you to experiment with. As always, Laidout is very much a work in progress,
so please let me know of any bugs you encounter!&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
What&apos;s not new is that there is still no native text tool. I swear I&apos;m working on it. What IS new in this release:&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A new alignment tool, allowing you to align objects to edges, on lay them out along paths, with various forms of rotation.
       &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gs8k4KUSkJw&quot;&gt;See here&lt;/a&gt; for a video tutorial&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A new n-up tool, which is used for laying out objects into rows and columns. Currently, you may only lay out in
	    grids where each cell is the same size, or grids where row heights and columns widths may vary. Also you may randomize
	    within the bounds of a rectangle. Future versions will let you flow objects into areas also.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The path tool has gotten some much needed attention. It hopefully crashes less, and is actually usable now. Improving that
       also debugged svg import so that paths import with an actual resemblance to the original svg!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The object tool now has little on canvas flip controls. Click on them to easily flip vertically or horizontally, or drag out
       one of them to define a flip line.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt; You may now define your own keyboard shortcuts. If you run &quot;laidout -S&quot;, it will output a dump of all currently bound
       shortcuts in text format, or &quot;laidout -H&quot; for an html dump. A downside currently is there is no editor in the program.
       You have to manually edit that dump, then put a line in
       your ~/.config/laidout/()version)/laidoutrc to say where the new shortcuts are. I&apos;m working on an editor.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
I have also been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tomlechner/3838153212&quot;&gt;working&lt;/a&gt; on a polyhedron unwrapper to be used with 
net impositions, but integration with Laidout is still not working. In the meantime, you could try the standalone unwrapper,
found in src/polyptych in downloaded source.
		 </description>
         <pubDate>17 July 2012</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 17 July 2012</guid>
      </item>



      <item>
         <title>Development update</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
So the new alignment tool is basically working, and the path tool has gotten some much needed attention.
Next up before a new Laidout release is a row-column arranging tool, and making the new opengl based
polyhedron unwrapper be usable for net impositions. Hopefully this will be "soon"!
In the meantime, here's a video demonstrating the current state of meshes. There are quirks and 
bugs here and there, but it is improving!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9YT5JIFEqm0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/www.laidout.org/screenshots/thumbs/meshes-0.093-s.png&quot; width=&quot;175&quot; height=&quot;137&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;		 
		 </description>
         <pubDate>6 July 2012</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 6 July 2012</guid>
      </item>


      
       <item>
         <title>Alignment tool preview, and this year's LGM</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=APGguBZOl10&quot;&gt;Behold&lt;/a&gt; a preview of a new alignment tool in Laidout! With it,
you may distribute sets of objects along paths. 
I hope someday to port (or help someone else port) this tool or some equivalent to Inkscape, where it would be most useful. 
I hope to smooth it out to show a less buggy version of this alignment tool at the Libre Graphics Meeting in early May
in Vienna, which I&apos;ll be going to.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.libregraphicsmeeting.org&quot;&gt;Libre Graphics Meeting&lt;/a&gt; is an annual gathering of users and developers of 
all kinds of open source graphics software.
This allows a kind of cross fertilization across projects resulting from face to face contact that might not otherwise happen
just from developing over the internet. &lt;a href=&quot;http://pledgie.com/campaigns/16614&quot;&gt;They are trying to raise money enough&lt;/a&gt; 
to cover travel costs of developers who otherwise could not afford to come.

	
		 </description>
         <pubDate>8 April 2012</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 8 April 2012</guid>
      </item>


      
      <item>
         <title>Laidout +1</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
There is now a new fangled &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/0/117350226436132405223&quot;&gt;Laidout Google+ page&lt;/a&gt;, for your amusement!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Also, Tom will be in Brussels soon for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lgru.net&quot;&gt;Libre Graphics Research Unit&apos;s&lt;/a&gt;
Co-Position meeting, to brainstorm with fellow interface explorers about possible futures of open source layout tools.
Click &lt;a href=&quot;http://lgru.net/archives/305&quot;&gt;here to
read an interview&lt;/a&gt; some of those folks did with Tom back in May on Laidout and related topics. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One last item, I uploaded new 0.092 versions to the download area, which fix a couple of bugs. One helps compiling on i386 systems,
which was breaking upon checking for Cups. The other is a greying out problem on the default Ubuntu desktop. Hopefully those
are fixed now. Let me know of other bugs you may encounter!
	
		 </description>
         <pubDate>11 February 2012</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 11 February 2012</guid>
      </item>


      
      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.092 Released. Woowoo!</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
Laidout Version 0.092 is at last 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laidout.org/#download&quot;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt;, as source or an  
amd64 precompiled deb package, for you to experiment with.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
What&apos;s not new is that there is still no native text tool. What IS new in this release:&lt;br&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is now an interface for modifying page labels. 
See a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6nViHfkPPjE&amp;list=UUbC0vtMKz_iq0AI1oXlJ42g&quot;&gt;video tutorial here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may now add custom printer marks, including some automatic marks if using signatures. Automarks are cut and fold
lines just outside the printable area, and/or tiny dots just inside the pages. The dots are useful in case you have no inset
in your signature. 
Work will be done hopefully soon to be able to customize various gaps, colors, and line widths of the automarks.
For custom marks, future versions will also provide much more control over which printer spreads get which printer marks. 
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is now a very basic path editing tool. It is somewhat new, and probably inadequate and buggy, but you can at least
build paths, and change the stroke and fill color with it. You cannot currently see transparency on screen in paths, but
it will export with transparency.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now select different units in the rulers. You can select a few common small units like inches, points, cm, mm, m, and yards.
Also you can select what units should be default units from the new document creation dialog.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scribus import has been slightly improved to handle page number labels, and master pages. Note however that the master pages
are converted to actual page objects on import. This simplifies exporting back out to a Scribus document after imposing onto
some bizarre layout. For the Scribus plugin, there are now a couple of Scribus based dialogs that can popup to try to get
settings to simplify calling laidout when things are not where they are expected. The automatic marks are available from
the Scribus plugin, but you cannot currently add your own custom ones. For that, you still have to import into a
running Laidout, not from the plugin. 
Read more about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laidout.org/scribus/index.html&quot;&gt;Laidout with Scribus here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now uses ~/.config/laidout to store options, rather than ~/.laidout. Also there is a Laidout .desktop file provided
to make it easier to access for those who don&apos;t like the command line.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsnarled some really convoluted behind the scenes object movement code. This finally makes moving groups of objects from
one page to another (or off of pages) actually work almost like one would expect it to. Still some serious problems moving objects
that are nested in groups though! A prime example of Laidout being a work in progress. I swear I&apos;m working on it.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few interface polishes, such as being able to click outside of a menu to make it go away, and tiny text writing in
the rulers that might make them actually useable.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
	
		 </description>
         <pubDate>30 December 2011</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 30 December 2011</guid>
      </item>


      
      <item>
         <title>Development Update</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
My goal is a new release of Laidout before January 1. Most changes are bug fixes and seemingly small interface smoothing,
the actual implementation of which is taking an annoyingly long time. The last major hurdle before releasing is to fix a very
mysterious paper tiling interface bug. It doesn&apos;t help that I&apos;m not quite sure when during the last nine months it stopped
working. You know you&apos;re in trouble when neither ddd nor valgrind give meaningful clues! Off to relearn
svn log/diff/co/update. If you don&apos;t know what that means, suffice it to say, it&apos;s really, really tedious!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
New features that are basically ready are the ability to use units other than inches, an interface to change page labels, rudimentary 
ability to add custom printer marks, and a more versatile Scribus importer. 
		 </description>
         <pubDate>30 November 2011</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 30 November 2011</guid>
      </item>


      
      <item>
         <title>New stuff and Libre Graphics Meeting recap</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
&lt;b&gt;Recent Additions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As seen in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tomlechner/3838153212/in/set-72157605559821149/&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;,
I&apos;ve been developing a 3-d polyhedron unwrapper, and panorama projector. I&apos;m slowly, bit by agonizing bit, 
making it directly available within Laidout. It is called Polyptych, and currently lives only in the 
Laidout svn. Once you &lt;a href=&quot;http://laidout.org/dev.html&quot;&gt;grab the Laidout svn&lt;/a&gt;,
go to src/impositions/polyptych, and you can build the standalone version. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Also, there does not appear to be an easy XInput2 configurator, so as to simply set up the use of
more than one mouse at the same time. Such a thing is needed to play with the newest faux multi-touch
capabilities of Laidout. To that end, I&apos;ve created a simple drag and drop configurator. This is
currently a part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://laxkit.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;Laxkit&lt;/a&gt; source code. Grab the
Laxkit svn, and go to the laxinput directory, and viola! Laxinput currently implements only the device
hierarchy changes, so for more complicated input mapping, you will still probably need xinput,
the command line utility that comes with the X window system, and perhaps xrandr.
Now if only Laxinput helped map strange input devices like IR spots from wiimotes, or tuio input to 
something usable for applications!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Laxinput is definitely experimental software. Use at your own risk!!
Both Polyptych (standalone and as a Laidout plugin), and Laxinput should be a little more stable
by the next release of Laidout, whenever that is! 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Libre Graphics Meeting recap&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This year&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.libregraphicsmeeting.org&quot;&gt;Libre Graphics Meeting&lt;/a&gt; in Montreal was again filled
with people from all over the world who make the software that I use all the time. I presented a short talk on
developments in Laidout during the last year. Also, I showed how I used a combination of Laidout, Inkscape, Gimp,
Blender, Polyptych, fabric and 40 iron on transfers to project a panoramic image onto a t-shirt. I&apos;m working
on a kind of tutorial of the process. People laughed, I am assuming at my jokes.
		 </description>
         <pubDate>30 May 2011</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 30 May 2011</guid>
      </item>


      <item>
         <title>Libre Graphics Meeting</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
Tom will be going to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.libregraphicsmeeting.org&quot;&gt;Libre Graphics Meeting&lt;/a&gt; this year in Montreal.
 If you can plan to be in Montreal May 10-13, you should come too!
 This meeting brings together free open source graphics software makers and users, to talk about what's going
on and what&apos;s to come, to collaborate and strategize.
 You can see the Laidout &lt;a href=&quot;http://river-valley.tv/laidout-and-desktop-publishing/&quot;&gt;presentation from last year here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you want to help support such an event, and also help those who want to come but can&apos;t otherwise afford the plane ticket,
you can donate to the Pledgie camipaign to raise money for it:&lt;br /&gt;
		 </description>
         <pubDate>13 April 2011</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 13 April 2011</guid>
      </item>


      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.091 Released</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
         Feast your eyes upon the latest release of Laidout! The hottest new things this time around
         are an on-screen folder to create signatures for imposing pages. There is a special command line
         flag that jumps you straight to this folding editor, which lets you do things like impose a Scribus
         document into a booklet, without ever leaving Scribus! There are also minor enhancements to
         the Spread Editor. Look for more on that front in the next release. Finally, there is a new
         exporter for PLAN files that podofoimpose can use to impose already existing pdf files. Yehaw!
		 </description>
         <pubDate>13 November 2010</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 13 November 2010</guid>
      </item>

      <item>
         <title>Still coming soon...</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
Here's a progress update. The signature editor is now in place, with fancy on screen folding. All that's left
before a release is debugging the Spread editor, and ironing out a few interface and
scripting annoyances. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Doing that should take about 2 weeks plus or minus a few weeks.
I swear. I really mean it this time. You can trust me. Is 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/metakephoto/5119193643/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; not a face you can trust? (Happy Halloween!)
		 </description>
         <pubDate>31 October 2010</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 31 October 2010</guid>
      </item>

      <item>
         <title>Coming soon...</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
         Just a few notes on coming changes to Laidout. Almost done is a folding signature imposition, where you can fold
the signature right on screen, and adjust trim and margin values, and which edge is supposed to be the binding
edge in a final book. This allows easy creation of both calendars and books with a single interface, as well as books
whose page numbers increase right to left.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Also in the works are the beginnings of multitouch capabilities. This is done with Xinput2, which lets you use
multiple mice at the same time, simulating touching a screen twice to do scaling and rotation by dragging
2 points around at the same time. The next Laidout version will only have this in the object tool, but
future versions will have that sort of thing more thoroughly available.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If I can stop being so lazy, the next version will come out within about a month. If I keep telling myself that,
it will be true someday, right?
		 </description>
         <pubDate>18 September 2010</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 18 September 2010</guid>
      </item>


      <item>
         <title>Laidout in Brussels</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
The annual &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.libregraphicsmeeting.org&quot;&gt;Libre Graphics Meeting&lt;/a&gt; for 2010 was held in Brussels,
 Belgium, and I was fortunate enough to be able to go and meet many of the makers of the software I use all the time.
  There were about 170 people from 47 different countries, each day was action packed with interesting talks about 
  lots of different programs and subjects. When navigating the streets of Brussels early in the morning trying to 
  find the conference, you simply have to throw out any preconceived ideas about urban planning, and this really 
  puts you in a great, open frame of mind when you finally get there and listen to the talks!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

I &lt;a href=&quot;http://river-valley.tv/laidout-and-desktop-publishing/&quot;&gt;presented Laidout&lt;/a&gt; 
and my interactive polyhedron unwrapper
 on the second day of the conference. People seemed 
to enjoy it. You can watch my talk, and all the other talks online, thanks to 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://river-valley.tv/conferences/lgm-2010&quot;&gt;River Valley TV&lt;/a&gt;. The LGM was certainly
 inspiration to get me to spend more time developing Laidout!
		 </description>
         <pubDate>9 June 2010</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 9 June 2010</guid>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.09 Released</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
         	Laidout 0.09 has just been released.

            New this time around are importers for Scribus, Svg, and Passepartout files.
            Also the ability to pass in rudimentary commands, letting you import, reimpose,
            and export all from the command line, without opening up any windows.

		 </description>
         <pubDate>21 February 2010</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 21 February 2007</guid>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.08 Released</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
         	Laidout 0.08 has just been released.

            New this time around are several new exporters for Pdf, Scribus, and transparent images.
            Also there is now a paper tiler for making large prints of a group of things using 
            many smaller pieces of paper.

		 </description>
         <pubDate>15 September 2007</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 15 September 2007</guid>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.06 Released</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
         	Laidout 0.06 has just been released.
         	
            Really not so very much is new, but there are a few notable improvements, such as the
            ability to import and print out EPS files. This lets you use pages made with other programs
            inside a Laidout document. Also new is the ability to start Laidout from a template document.

		 </description>
         <pubDate>21 April 2007</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 21 April 2007</guid>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.05 Released</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
         	Laidout 0.05 has just been released.
         	
         	Only one month late this time, now you can work using preview images,
         	so that you don't run out of memory moving around hundreds of huge tiffs. 
         	Also, you can now import multiple images at once from a file list. Plus the
         	object tool now uses a three point transform for speedy positioning. See
         	the website for more.

		 </description>
         <pubDate>4 November 2006</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 4 November 2006</guid>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>Laidout 0.04 Released</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org</link>
         <description>
         	So just in case anyone's watching, Laidout 0.04 has just been released.
         	
         	The biggest news for this much delayed release is a Palette window, in 
            which you can select a color, and have that color immediately applied 
            to whatever you're working on. Also, Laidout now uses icons, and the 
            splittable window system has been improved. 

		 </description>
         <pubDate>4 September 2006</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 4 September 2006</guid>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>Making zines with open source software</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org/index.html#events</link>
         <description>
         	Laidout development will be rather slow until mid-August. The development
         	team (consisting of a one Tom Lechner) is spending most of his time finishing
         	a book of cartoons (which he's put off finishing for about 6 months) in time
         	 to show off at the Portland Zine Syposium August 11-13 in
         	Portland, Oregon (http://www.pdxzines.com).
         	At the symposium I'll also be giving a workshop on how to
        	 	make zines using all open source software including Laidout, Scribus, the Gimp,
        	 	Inkscape, and more.
		 </description>
         <pubDate>9 July 2006</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>Laidout 9 July 2006</guid>
      </item>
      
      <item>
         <title>New screenshot of a rhombic triacontahedron</title>
         <link>http://www.laidout.org/shots/screenshots.html#triacontahedron</link>
         <description>
				This screenshot shows a Net Imposition as seen in the development version.
				This particular net is a 30 sided Rhombic Triacontahedron layout, that 
				one might use to make spherical panoramas..
		 </description>
         <pubDate>18 June 2006</pubDate> <!-- Tue, 03 Jun 2003 09:39:21 GMT -->
         <guid>18 June 2006</guid>
      </item>
   </channel>
</rss>
